Derek Mahon papers, circa 1948-2008
Emory University
- Printed material, Series 4; Box 39 - Box 43; OP5-11
  - Printed material by Derek Mahon, Subseries 4.1; Box 39 - Box 40
    - "Grey Gowrie: Ideas of Order and Late-Century Blues" in Vogue, January 1975 (Box 39, Folder 22)
    - "A Handful of Dust" [review of In Society], 16 August 1986 (Box 39, Folder 23)
    - "The Hare and the Tortoise" [review of Yeats and AE, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 24)
    - Hermathena [including poetry by Derek Mahon], Summer 1994 (Box 39, Folder 25)
    - "Hugo Williams, Poet" in Vogue, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 26)
    - "Interpretative Centers," letter to the editor (Box 39, Folder 27)
    - "Introduction" to Words in the Air (Box 39, Folder 28)
    - Ireland of the Welcomes 45.5 (September 1996), edited by DM ["New Irish Writing"] (Box 39, Folder 29)
    - "Irish of the Orient" [review of Tilting the Jar, Spilling the Moon] (Box 39, Folder 30)
    - "Jardin du Luxembourg" in Times Literary Supplement, 2 June 2006 (Box 39, Folder 31)
    - "Jean Rhys in Kettner's" in The Guardian, 2 April 2005 (Box 39, Folder 32)
    - "Joyce's wild goose" [review of Nora: A Biography of Nora Joyce], in The Irish Times, 18 June 1988 (Box 39, Folder 33)
    - Juvenilia published in the Royal Belfast Academical Institution's School News [includes TLS, 16 January 2002, from Hugh Haughton] (Box 39, Folder 34)
    - "Keeping the Anglo-Irish alive" [review of Twilight of the Ascendency], in The Spectator, 24 January 1987 (Box 39, Folder 35)
    - "A Kensington Notebook" in PN Review 9.6, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 36)
    - "King of the Cats" [review of Tuohy's Yeats] in New Statesman, 5 November 1976 (Box 39, Folder 37)
    - Kitap [inc. Turkish translations of Mahon's poetry] (Box 39, Folder 38)
    - "Letter from New York: A Latter-Day Dunciad" (Box 39, Folder 39)
    - "Letter from New York: Bright Lights Burn On" (Box 39, Folder 40)
    - "Letter from New York: History and the higher gossip" (Box 39, Folder 41)
    - "Letter from New York: Just Kidding" (Box 39, Folder 42)
    - "Letter from New York: With Beckett in the Hamptons" (Box 39, Folder 43)
    - "Letters found in a bottle" [review of The Thirsty Muse] (Box 39, Folder 44)
    - "Lucretius on Clouds" in the Times Literary Supplement, 11 February 2005 (Box 39, Folder 45)
    - "More Older Women" [review of Truth and Lies in Literature], The Irish Times (Box 39, Folder 46)
    - Night-Crossing, photocopy with corrections and inserted TS (Box 39, Folder 47)
    - "Noon at St. Michaels" [See Subseries 4.1: "Amores IV"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Natural and Immeasurable Wonder of Achill," n.d. (Box 39, Folder 48)
    - "Orpheus Ascending: The Poetry of Paul Durcan" in The Irish Review 1, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 49)
    - "Pagan Place" [review of Mother Ireland] in New Statesman, 4 June 1976 (Box 39, Folder 50)
    - "Palinurus and his Byzantine empire" [review Friends of Promise] in The Irish Times, 22 April 1989 (Box 39, Folder 51)
    - "The Pick of the Crop" [review of Windy Arbours: Collected Criticism by Aidan Higgins[ in The Irish Times, 29 July 2006 (Box 39, Folder 52)
    - "A Portrait of Robert Lowell" in The Listener, 6 December 1984 (Box 39, Folder 53)
    - "The Pre-Natal Mountain: Louis MacNeice's Ireland" in Ireland of the Welcomes, 56.4, July-August 2007 (Box 39, Folder 54)
    - "Proust Chat" [review of Marcel Proust: A Centenary Volume], in The Listener, 26 August 1971 (Box 39, Folder 55)
    - "The Prudence Farmer Poetry Prize" in New Statesman, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 56)
    - "The Remarkable Rocketeer who Fell to Earth" [review of The Fireworks of Oscar Wilde] (Box 39, Folder 57)
    - "Resistance Days" in The London Review of Books, 25 April 2002 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - "Reveller at Life's Feast" [excerpt from the Introduction to Jonathan Swift: Poems] in The Guardian, 4 March 2006 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - "River Rhymes" in Soho Square, ed. Colm Toibín, 1993 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - "Rock 'n' Roll is Here to Stay" [review of Slow Learner: Early Stories], in The Literary Review, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - "Sam – the artist as hero" [review of Samuel Beckett: The Last Modernist] in Sunday Independent, 27 October 1996 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - “The Seaside Cemetery” in the Times Literary Supplement, 7 September 2001 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - “Shapes and Shadows” in The Irish Times, 29 June 2002 [includes TLS from Angela Reid and copy of Shapes and Shadows by William Scott] (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - "Shiver in your Tenement" n.d. (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - "Slight Angle" [review of Cavafy] in New Statesman, 14 February 1975 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - "Splendid Isolation," in Departures, May/June 1987 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Swiat Literacki [Irish poetry special issue], 1993 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - "'That Enquiring Man'" in Ireland of the Welcomes 47.4 (July 1997) (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - "This Dump, This Dump" [review of A Pagan Place], in The Listener, 23 April 1970 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - "Tithonos" in recueil, no. 18 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - "The Wanderings of JBY" [review of Prodigal Father: The Life of John Butler Yeats], in New Statesman 18 August 1978, fragment (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - When the Tunnels Meet [DM's translations of poetry by Cezar Baltag] (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - "Wild Harp of Erin" [review of Kinsella, Muldoon anthologies], incomplete (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - "Womanly Times" [review of Selected Letters of Robert Graves], in Literary Review, September 1984 (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - W.P Journal [inc. poetry by Derek Mahon], March-April 1998 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - "Yeats and the Lights of Dublin" in The Dublin Review, Autumn 2002 (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - Untitled [review of Langrishe, Go Down by Aidan Higgins] in The Sunday Times, 28 January 1996 [includes ALS from Maeve] (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - Source material for Derek Mahon bibliography (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - Source material for Derek Mahon bibliography (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - Source material for Derek Mahon bibliography (Box 40, Folder 24)
    - Source material for Derek Mahon bibliography (Box 40, Folder 25)
    - Derek Mahon bibliography, draft (Box 40, Folder 26)
    - Derek Mahon bibliography, draft (Box 40, Folder 27)
    - Letters by DM to newspapers (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - Printed material about Derek Mahon, Subseries 4.2; Box 40 - Box 41a (folder 12); OP5-10
    The subseries contains reviews of Mahon's poetry, essays about his work, and miscellaneous materials relating to his work.
    - Reviews
    - Night Crossing (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Lives (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Poems, 1962-1978 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - The Hunt by Night (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Courtyards in Delft (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - The School for Wives (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - "The Cry" (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Selected Poems (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Journalism (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - The Hudson Letter (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Corrected proof of Lucy McDiarmid's review of The Hudson Letter (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - "Racine's Phaedra" (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - "Racine's Phaedra," bound folder of reviews (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - The Yellow Book (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Collected Poems (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Selected Poems (2000) (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - Jonathan Swift: Poems (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Poems / Patrick MacDonogh (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - Harbour Lights (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Selected Poems, Expanded Edition (2006) (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - Adaptations [See Subseries 4.2, Reviews, Selected Poems, Expanded Edition (2006)] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Essays/Articles
    - "Beyond Fear and Fascination: Women in the Poetry of Derek Mahon" by Fleur Fitzgerald (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - "Booking Now for 2100" [article on RTÉ's Reading the Future] by Fintan O'Toole in The Irish Times, 4 November 2000 (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - "Cultivating the Element of Surprise" [article on W.S. Merwin] by Belinda McKeon (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - "Derek Mahon: Bibliography" by Jody Allen-Randolph in Irish University Review, annotated by DM (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - "Derek Mahon Interviewed," in Poetry Review (Summer 1991) (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - "Derek Mahon: Keeping the Language Efficient" by Gerald Dawe in The Journal of Irish Studies, 2006 [photocopy] (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - "Derek Mahon: The Poet and Painting" by Terence Brown in Irish University Review (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - "Derek Mahon: The World as Exile" by Sean O'Brien in The Deregulated Muse (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - "Derek Mahon's Lost Domain" by Charles O'Neill in The Recorder, Spring 1997 (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - "Elegy to MacNeice" (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - "Going Home: Northern Ireland and Derek Mahon's The Hunt by Night" by Hugh Haughton (Box 41, Folder 32)
    - "In the Heaven of Lost Futures" [review of Eavan Boland's New Collected Poems] by John Redmond in The Guardian, 18 February 2006 (Box 41, Folder 33)
    - "Introduction" by John Banville to J.G. Farrell's Troubles (Box 41, Folder 34)
    - "Ireland's Derek Mahon: 'Teaching English to Engineers'" by Patrick Keefe (Box 41, Folder 35)
    - "An Ironic Conscience at One Minute to Midnight" by Edna Longley in Fortnight, 17 December 1984 (Box 41, Folder 36)
    - Letters to the Editor in the Times Literary Supplement, 14 May 2004 (Box 41, Folder 37)
    - "Mahon's Islands" by Enrico Reggiani in The Classical World and the Mediterranean (Box 41, Folder 38)
    - "Middle Man," Interview with Michael Longley by Nicholas Wroe in The Guardian, 21 August 2004 (Box 41, Folder 39)
    - "The Name Rings a Bell: Louis MacNeice's Northern Ireland" by Colin Graham (Box 41, Folder 40)
    - "Nella sua Poesia di Derek Mahon," "Derek Mahon, 'bohémien irlandese,'" and article in Versodove, all by Roberto Bertoni (Box 41, Folder 41)
    - Obituary of Philip Hobsbaum by Alan Brownjohn in The Guardian, 7 July 2005 (Box 41, Folder 42)
    - "On Sitting Down to Read 'A Disused Shed in Co. Wexford' Once Again" by Hugh Haughton, in The Cambridge Quarterly, 2002 (Box 41, Folder 43)
    - "The Poet's Poet" [article about Elizabeth Bishop] by Tom Paulin in The Irish Times, 11 September 2004 (Box 41, Folder 44)
    - "A Sense of Place" by Nicholas Wroe, The Guardian, 22 July 2006 (Box 41, Folder 45)
    - "Six Poets Respond to Derek Mahon's Harbour Lights" by Vona Groarke, Justin Quinn, Gerard Fanning, John McAuliffe, Siobhán Campbell, and Conor O'Callaghan, in Poetry Ireland Review, October 2005 (Box 41, Folder 46)
    - "A Week in Books" by Boyd Tonkin [article about Mahon's winning the David Cohen Prize] in The Independent, 23 March 2007 (Box 41, Folder 47)
    - "The World of Derek Mahon" by Paul Durcan in Magill, December 1984 (Box 41, Folder 48)
    - Miscellaneous
    - "Chekhov on Sakhalin" for Derek Mahon, by Seamus Heaney (Box 41a, Folder 1)
    - Clippings and promotional material about The Hudson Letter Broadcast, 25 December 2001, on RTÉ (Box 41a, Folder 2)
    - Letters to the editor re: "Poets Galore" (Box 41a, Folder 3)
    - Playbill for The School for Wives (Box 41a, Folder 4)
    - "Poets and Writers" exhibition pamphlet, BBC Northern Ireland (Box 41a, Folder 5)
    - Promotional material-miscellaneous (Box 41a, Folder 6)
    - Promotional material-Princeton University reading, poster (Box OP5)
    - Promotional material-Library of Congress reading, broadside (Box OP6)
    - Promotional material-SUNY reading, broadside (2 copies) (Box OP7)
    - Promotional material-Joycentenary Ode (Box OP8)
    - Promotional material-The School for Wives, poster (Box OP9)
    - Promotional material-The School forWives, poster (Box OP10)
    - Public Relations material (Box 41a, Folder 7)
    - Reading the Future, RTÉ Radio 1, Souvenir Calendar 2001 (Box 41a, Folder 8)
    - Review of In the Chair: Interviews with Poets from the North of Ireland, edited by John Brown (Box 41a, Folder 9)
    - Review of The Poetry of Derek Mahon, edited by Elmer Kennedy-Jones (Box 41a, Folder 10)
    - RTÉ Guide featuring Mahon's The Bacchae of Euripides as Play of the Week, September 2000 (Box 41a, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous clippings about DM (Box 41a, Folder 12)
  - General printed material, Subseries 4.3; Box 41a (folder 13) - Box 43; OP11
    - Essays: "A Box for Wilfrid Blunt" by Lucy McDiarmid, in PMLA (Box 41a, Folder 13)
    - Essays: "In Conversation with Stephen Rea" by Luke Gibbons and Kevin Whelan, in The Yale Journal of Criticism, 2002 (Box 41a, Folder 14)
    - Essays: Excerpt from Ezra Pound's Hugh Selwyn Mauberley by Donald Davie (Box 41a, Folder 15)
    - Essays: "Humane Killer" by Cyril Connolly in London Magazine, 1973 (Box 41a, Folder 16)
    - Essays: "Liberating the Pseudoese" by Lucy McDiarmid in The Yale Review (Box 41a, Folder 17)
    - Essays: "The Memories of 'The Dead'" by Kevin Whelan, in The Yale Journal of Criticism, 2002 (Box 41a, Folder 18)
    - Essays: "Poetry Between Two Worlds" by Jean Starobinski (Box 41a, Folder 19)
    - Essays: "'Rough Hands and a Sick Culture': The Irish Writer and Cultural Tourism" in Irish University Review (Box 41a, Folder 20)
    - Essays: "Slippery Sam and Tomtinker Tim: Beckett and MacGreevy's Urban Poetics" by David Wheatley in Irish Studies Review, 2005 [includes ALS from Wheatley, n.d.] (Box 41a, Folder 21)
    - Essays: "Yeats's Politics Since 1943: Approaches and Reproaches" by W.J. McCormack, in The Yearbook of English Studies, 2005 (Box 41a, Folder 22)
    - Essays, miscellaneous (Box 41a, Folder 23)
    - Essays, miscellaneous (Box 41a, Folder 24)
    - Essays, miscellaneous (Box 41a, Folder 25)
    - Museum and art exhibition guides (Box 41a, Folder 26)
    - Newspaper clippings with literary subjects (Box 41a, Folder 27)
    - Newspaper clippings with literary subjects (Box 41a, Folder 28)
    - Newspaper clippings with literary subjects (Box 41a, Folder 29)
    - Newspaper clippings with literary subjects (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings with literary subjects (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings with literary subjects: "Burial at Thebes" by Seamus Heaney in The Guardian, 21 February 2004 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Other newspaper clippings (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Other newspaper clippings (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Other newspaper clippings (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Other newspaper clippings (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Other newspaper clippings (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Other newspaper clippings (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Other newspaper clippings (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Other printed material with literary subjects (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Other printed material (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Other printed material (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Playbills (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Playbills (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Playbills and promotional materials from theaters (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Poster: Peter Kelly, "Art of an Era" (Box OP11)
    - Prospectus for a volume of Samuel Beckett's Foirades with etchings by Jasper Johns (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Title page of The Testament of Cresseid by Seamus Heaney (Box 43, Folder 8)
- Photographs and audiovisual materials, Series 5; Box 44 - Box 46a
  Series 5 consists of photographs and audiovisual media from circa 1960-2005. There are a few early photographs here, although the bulk of the photographs are from the 1980s and 1990s. There are a number of photographs of Mahon with other literary figures, as well as pictures of geographic locations that feature in his poetry. The audiovisual section contains a number of recordings of Mahon reading his poetry, including his reading at Emory University in 1996.
  Organized into two subseries: (5.1) Photographs and (5.2) Audiovisual material.
  Researchers must contact MARBL in advance to access audiovisual material in this collection.
  - Photographs, Subseries 5.1; Box 44 - Box 45
    - Photographs of Derek Mahon
    - Childhood photographs (5 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Glengormley, 1960 (2 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - DM at the "Windsor Castle," London, 1971 (2 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - DM and Doreen, Wedding, December 1972 (4 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - DM in Lingfield, ca. 1976 (3 photographs, one including Michael Longley) (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - DM, Cathal O'Learcaigh, Patricia King, Winston Salem, 1982? (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - DM in Paris, 1989 (2 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - DM in Boston, ca. 1991 (3 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - DM, New York, [ca. 1992] (4 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Clipping of DM from The Irish Times, ca. 1992 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Newport, Co. Mayo, August 1993 (3 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - DM, New York, 1994 (3 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - DM in Dublin, 1994 (2 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - DM with Frank Platt, New York, October 1994 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - DM in Key West, June 1995 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - DM at the United Arts Club with C.P. (Robin) Fogarty, Richard Ryan, and Sean Mac Réamoinn, November 1995 (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Series of photographs of DM by Bill Doyle, circa November 1995 (5 photographs and 3 contact prints) (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - DM reading at Waterstone's, circa November 1995 (6 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - DM at Ireland House, NYU, 1995 (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - DM at the Ireland House, January 1996 (2 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - Photographs of DM at Emory, 30 January 1996 (5 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - DM, Prague, April 1996 (Box 44, Folder 22)
    - DM and Clare Carroll at the Shelbourne Hotel, 1997 (Box 44, Folder 23)
    - DM and Brendan Kennelly, October 1997 (2 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 24)
    - DM and John Minihan, Dublin, 1998 (Box 44, Folder 25)
    - DM in Venice, circa 1999 (Box 44, Folder 26)
    - DM and J.P. Donleavy, March 2000 (Box 44, Folder 27)
    - DM and Patricia King, Dublin, June 2000 (Box 44, Folder 28)
    - DM, July 2000 (21 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 29)
    - DM, Brendan Kennelly, and Patricia King, Ballybunion, August 2000 (3 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 30)
    - Portrait of DM by Tom Haran, 2002 (Box 44, Folder 31)
    - Portrait of DM by Anthony Palliser, 2002 (Box 44, Folder 32)
    - DM, November 2004 (Box 44, Folder 33)
    - DM, 2005 (6 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 34)
    - DM and Hugh Haughton, August 2005 (2 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 35)
    - DM, 2007 (6 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 36)
    - Undated photographs of DM (Box 44, Folder 37)
    - Photographs of Derek Mahon's family
    - Family photographs (Box 44, Folder 38)
    - Rory Mahon, Portballintrae, 1978 (Box 44, Folder 39)
    - Derek and Katie Mahon, York, 1998 (Box 44, Folder 40)
    - DM and children, circa August 1999 (Box 44, Folder 41)
    - Katie Mahon, York, 1999 (Box 44, Folder 42)
    - Katie Mahon, Shepherd's Bush, circa 1999 (5 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 43)
    - Rory Mahon, 2002-2003 (12 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 44)
    - Maisie Mahon, 2004 (5 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 45)
    - Maisie Mahon, May 2005 (6 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 46)
    - Maisie Mahon and Jane, August 2005 (7 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 47)
    - Maisie Mahon, circa 2006-2007 (Box 44, Folder 48)
    - Rory and Katie Mahon (3 photographs) (Box 44, Folder 49)
    - Groups of photographs
    - Paul Jackel and still-life, Toronto, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 50)
    - DM in New York with Patricia King, May-June 1995 (Box 44, Folder 51)
    - DM in Italy with Patricia King, ca. 1998-2000 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - DM in Paros, Greece, August 1997 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - DM in Montreux, Switzerland, January 1998 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - DM's flat in Fitzwilliam Square, Dublin, ca. 1995-2000 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Clouds by John Minihan, 2001 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Belfast and Cushenden, 2002 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Kinsale 2002, from John Minihan (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Ballydehob with clouds by John Minihan, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - DM in Prague, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - DM in Cushenden, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Photographs of Synge's cottage, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - "Vanessa's house and bower," Co. Kildare, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Laracor, Co. Meath, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Photographs re. Elizabeth Bowen, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - St. Patrick's Memorial Church and P. King in Co. Down, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Portrush: Craigvara House and "the sea in winter," n.d. (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - The Grove, Kinsale (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous photographs
    - Samuel Beckett, London 1980 and the Wake of Katie Tyrell, 1977 [includes APS, 6 February 2001, from John Minihan] (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - Beckett in Paris, 1985, by John Minihan (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Samuel Beckett, Paris, December 1985 (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - Richard Ryan, London, circa 1985 (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - Stephen Rea, London 1987 (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - Philippe Jacottet, London, 1988 (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - Lingfield, 1995 (2 photographs) (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - Patricia King, graduation, May 1996 (Box 45, Folder 25)
    - Gareth Brown and Michael O'Sullivan, the Shelbourne, 2000 (Box 45, Folder 26)
    - Sarah Owens and Patricia King, at "Beckett on Film," Dublin Castle, 2001 (Box 45, Folder 27)
    - Old Head, Kinsale, Co. Cork, by John Minihan, 2002 (Box 45, Folder 28)
    - Dylan and Caitlin Thomas's gravesite, January 2003 (5 photographs) (Box 45, Folder 29)
    - Michael Longley, Edna Longley, Sarah Longley, and family, 2006 (6 photographs) (Box 45, Folder 30)
    - Tom Haran with portrait of DM (Box 45, Folder 31)
    - Patricia King in Newport, Co. Mayo (Box 45, Folder 32)
    - John Montague in Kinsale (3 photographs) (Box 45, Folder 33)
    - Francis Stuart (Box 45, Folder 34)
    - Seamus Heaney and Joseph Brodsky (Box 45, Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 45, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous negatives (Box 45, Folder 37)
  - Audiovisual materials, Subseries 5.2; Box 46 - Box 46a
    - Audiotapes
    - Derek Mahon reads from "The Hudson Letter" [place and date unknown] [digitized; b4v5w] (Box 46)
    - "An Evening of Irish Poetry with Derek Mahon," Emory University, 29 January 1996 [digitized; filename 3936-3937] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Mahon, Derek, "A Grafted Tongue: A Portrait of John Montague" by Derek Mahon, no date[digitized; filename bscxs] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Jack MacGowran reads poems by Samuel Beckett, Claddagh Media, January 21, 1996 [digitized; filename 3940, 3947] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "MacGowran Speaking Beckett," Claddagh Media, November 11, 1996 [digitized; filename: 3948-3949] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Phaedra, radio play for RTÉ (Box 46)
    - "The Poet's Voice" - Dylan Thomas [digitized; filename 3938] (Box 46)
    - "A Sense of Place" [interview of and reading by Derek Mahon], BBC, 12 February 1984 [digitized; b4v75, b4v61] (Box 46)
    - Unidentified Irish Language Tape [1 tape] (Box 46)
    - Compact Discs
    - The Hudson Letter, radio version read by Stephen Rea, RTÉ, 25 December 2001 [digitized; filename 3939] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Louis MacNeice -- the Celt, the Cat, and the Cave," BBC Radio 3, presented by Paul Muldoon and featuring Derek Mahon and others, 9 September 2007 (Box -, Folder -)
    - Martijn Voorvelt, Hondsdagen (Dog Days), for (amateur) mixed choir, on poems by Derek Mahon and Bert Schierbeck, and Raging, building (Box 46)
    - "Never a Day Without a Line: Derek Mahon on Olivia Manning," 23 July 1981 (Box 46)
    - Oedipus by Derek Mahon, RTÉ, Part One: Oedipus Rex, 6 November 2005 (Box 46)
    - Oedipus by Derek Mahon, RTÉ, Part Two: Oedipus at Colonus, 6 November 2005 (Box 46)
    - The Road to Colonus by George Mackay Brown, RTÉ, 6 March 1990 (Box 46)
    - Videotapes
    - "Derek Mahon" [Lannan Literary Video #38; reading and interview on 8 March, 1994 [digitized; filename 9762] (Box 46a)
- Legal and financial records, Series 6; Box 47